Guide to the Civic Repertory Theatre Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Civic Repertory Theatre records
1917-1985
1925-1936
YCAL MSS 343
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
13.84
(32 boxes) + 1 portfolio,1 broadside folder
The Civic Repertory Theatre Records consist of production files containing scripts, promptbooks, technical production documentation, manuscript and printed music, and photographs; financial records including auditor's financial statements, box office receipts, weekly financial statements, and ledgers; programs, issues of the Civic Repertory Theatre Bulletin/Magazine and other printed material; notebooks containing Eva Le Gallienne's translations of plays by Henrik Ibsen; and pressbooks and scrapbooks. Also found are materials documenting some of Le Gallienne's post-Civic Rep productions, including photoduplications of costume designs by Patricia Zipprodt for Le Gallienne's 1982 revival of Alice in Wonderland, as well as a small group of material relating to the Bonstelle Playhouse of Detroit, Michigan, which documents the work of actor Donald Cameron, also a member of the Civic Repertory Theatre.
Civic Repertory Theatre, Inc
Le Gallienne, Eva, 1899-1991
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eva Le Gallienne, 1960, 1964, 1983, and Thelma Chandler, 1962.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Civic Repertory Theatre
The Civic Repertory Theatre was established by Eva Le Gallienne in New York City in 1926. Le Gallienne directed and acted in most of the rotating repertory of classical plays. The company disbanded in 1933, and Le Gallienne continued to act and direct stage productions, including a 1982 revival of Alice in Wonderland.
Scope and Contents
The Civic Repertory Theatre Records consist of production files containing scripts, promptbooks, technical production documentation, manuscript and printed music, and photographs; financial records including auditor's financial statements, box office receipts, weekly financial statements, and ledgers; programs, issues of the Civic Repertory Theatre Bulletin / Magazine and other printed material; notebooks containing Eva Le Gallienne's translations of plays by Henrik Ibsen; and pressbooks and scrapbooks. Also found are materials documenting some of Le Gallienne's post-Civic Rep productions, including photoduplications of costume designs by Patricia Zipprodt for Le Gallienne's 1982 revival of Alice in Wonderland, as well as a small group of material relating to the Bonstelle Playhouse of Detroit, Michigan, which documents the work of actor Donald Cameron, also a member of the Civic Repertory Theatre.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Production Files, 1925-1982. II. Financial Records, 1926-1935. III. Pressbooks, 1923-1962. IV. Administrative Files, 1926-1964. V. Photographs, 1917-1953. VI. Eva Le Gallienne Writings and Memorabilia, 1932.
Theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Photographs; Prompt books; Scrapbooks; Cameron, Donald, 1889-1955; Le Gallienne, Eva, 1899-1991; Zipprodt, Patricia, 1925-1999; Civic Repertory Theatre, Inc
- Production Files, 1925-1982; Series I; 4; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title of production.
  Scope and Contents
  Files for each production may contain scripts, promptbooks, material relating to design and technical aspects of the production, photographs, and music.
  - L'Aiglon, 1934; 3 (Box 1)
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1932-1933, 1982; 6 (Box 1)
    Includes photoduplications of costume designs by Patricia Zipprodt for the 1982 revival of Alice in Wonderland
  - Alison's House, 1930-1931; 4 (Box 1)
  - Camille, 1931; 3 (Box 2)
  - Cherry Orchard, 1928; 3 (Box 2)
  - Cradle Song, 1927, 1930; 3 (Box 2)
  - Dear Jane, 1932; 2 (Box 2)
  - A Doll's House, 1934 (Box 2)
  - The First Stone, 1928; 2 (Box 2)
  - The Good Hope, 1927; 2 (Box 2)
  - The Green Cockatoo, 1930; 3 (Box 2)
  - Hedda Gabler, 1928, 1930; 2 (Box 2)
  - Improvisations in June, 1928; 3 (Box 2)
  - L'Invitation au Voyage, 1928; 4 (Box 2)
  - John Gabriel Borkman, 1926; 3 (Box 2)
  - Katerina, 1929; 2 (Box 2)
  - Lady from Alfaqueque, 1929; 2 (Box 2)
  - Liliom, 1932; 3 (Box 3)
  - The Living Corpse, 1929 (Box 3)
  - La Locandiera, 1926-1927; 5 (Box 3)
  - Mademoiselle Bourrat, 1929; 2 (Box 3)
  - The Master Builder, 1925-1926; 3 (Box 3)
  - On the High Road, 1929; 2 (Box 3)
  - Peter Pan, 1928; 3 (Box 3)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1930; 2 (Box 3)
  - Rosmersholm, 1935; 2 (Box 3)
  - Saturday Night, 1926 (Box 4)
  - The Sea Gull, 1930; 2 (Box 4)
  - Siegfried, 1930; 2 (Box 4)
  - A Sunny Morning, 1935; 3 (Box 4)
  - The Three Sisters, 1926; 4 (Box 4)
  - Twelfth Night, 1926; 3 (Box 4)
  - 2 x 2 = 5, 1927; 2 (Box 4)
  - The Women Have Their Way, 1930; 3 (Box 4)
  - The Would-Be Gentleman, 1928; 4 (Box 4)
- Financial Records, 1926-1935; Series II; 4.67; (11 boxes)
  Arranged chronologically within type of record.
  This series consists of materials documenting the finances of the Civic Repertory Theatre, including ledgers maintained by staff and statements from the company's auditors.
  - Auditor's financial statements, 1926-1928; 5 (Box 5)
  - Auditor's financial statements, 1929-1931; 8 (Box 6)
  - Auditor's financial statements, 1932-1935; 5 (Box 7)
  - Weekly financial statements, 1927-1933; 4 (Box 7)
  - Monthly financial statements, 1931-1932 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous financial statements, 1926-1933; 3 (Box 7)
  - Box office statements, 1926-1933; 6 (Box 8)
  - Ledgers
    - Productions, 1926-1932; 5 (Box 9)
    - "Accessions", undated (Box 9)
    - Cash disbursements, 1926-1928 (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Cash disbursements, 1928 May-1929 Nov (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Cash disbursements, 1929 Nov-1931 Feb (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Cash disbursements, 1931 Feb-1932 Dec (Box 13 (Oversize))
    - Production costs, undated (Box 14 (Oversize))
    - Cash receipts, "old" and "new", 1926-1930; 2 (Box 15 (Oversize))
- Pressbooks, 1923-1962; Series III; 1.75; (7 boxes)
  Arranged by subject.
  This series consists of pressbooks containing press clippings relating to Civic Repertory Theatre productions and company members. The pressbooks are accompanied by a scrapbook containing examples of stationery and other Civic Repertory Theatre printed items.
  - New York City, 1926 May-Nov; 2 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - New York City, 1926 Nov-1927 Apr; 2 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Tour, 1926 Aug-1927 Apr; 3 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Tour, 1927 May-Jun (Box 19 (Oversize))
  - Advance notices, 1926-1935; 2 (Box 19 (Oversize))
  - Various productions, 1929-1935; 4 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Loose press clippings, 1923-1933; 2 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Eva Le Gallienne press clippings, 1930-1932, 1962 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Eva Le Gallienne press books and loose clippings, 1926-1934; 4 (Box 21 (Oversize))
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Oversize box 33, Portfolio 33, and Broadside 34
  - Various productions, 1926-1930 (Box 22 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook of examples of Civic Repertory Theatre printed ephemera, 1932-1933 (Box 22 (Oversize))
- Administrative Files, 1926-1964; Series IV; 1; (1 box)
  Arranged by type of material.
  This series consists of material relating to the administration of the CRT, including information on company personnel, performance schedules, and publications by and about the Civic Repertory Theatre.
  - Weekly schedules of performances, 1927-1930; 2 (Box 23)
  - Production programs, 1926-1933; 10 (Box 23)
  - Civic Repertory Theatre Bulletin / Civic Repertory Theatre Magazine, 1930-1931 (Box 23)
  - The Civic Repertory Theatre 1926-1932, 2 (Box 23)
  - Lists of productions, 1926-1930 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 23)
  - List of company members, undated (Box 23)
  - Touring schedule, 1934-1935 (Box 23)
  - Inventory of electrical equipment, undated (Box 23)
  - Bibliography of articles about the Civic Repertory Theatre, [1932?] (Box 23)
  - Texts from various plays, undated (Box 23)
  - Galleys for Alice in Wonderland as performed by the Civic Repertory Theatre (Samuel French), undated (Box 23)
  - Galleys (incomplete) for Camille as performed by the Civic Repertory Theatre (Samuel French), undated (Box 23)
  - National Repertory Theatre program from Shubert Theatre (New Haven, Connecticut), 1964 (Box 23)
- Photographs, 1917-1953, undated; Series V; 0.75; (3 boxes)
  This series contains photographs of company members, production photographs, costume designs, as well as photographs of non-Civic Repertory Theatre productions including those of the Bonstelle Playhouse of Detroit in which Donald Cameron was involved prior to his work with the Civic Repertory Theatre.
  - Civic Repertory Theatre building, undated (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Company members in unidentified productions, undated (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Costumes designs of Russian army officers, undated (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Non-Civic Repertory Theatre productions, undated (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Non-Civic Repertory Theatre productions, 1925-1953, undated; 2 (Box 25 (Oversize))
  - Bonstelle Playhouse (Detroit) productions, 1925 (Box 25 (Oversize))
  - Bonstelle Playhouse (Detroit) company members (including Donald Cameron), undated (Box 26 (Oversize))
  - Donald Cameron photographs and scrapbook, 1917-1924; 2 (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Eva Le Gallienne Writings and Memorabilia, 1932, undated; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  This series contains the writings of dramatic criticism and memoirs by Le Gallienne and others. The writings are accompanied by a scrapbook about Le Gallienne compiled by A. M. Weil as a gift to her.
  - Notes on, and translations of, Ibsen plays [for Modern Library publication], undated
    - The Enemy of the People, undated (Box 27)
    - Hedda Gabler, undated (Box 27)
    - The Lady from the Sea, undated (Box 27)
    - Little Eyolf, undated (Box 27)
    - The Master Builder, undated (Box 27)
    - Pillars of Society, undated (Box 27)
    - When We Dead Awaken, undated (Box 27)
    - The Wild Duck, undated (Box 27)
  - "Backstage in a Repertory Theatre", undated (Box 27)
  - Notes on the history of the Civic Repertory Theatre, undated (Box 27)
  - "My Friendship with Ibsen" by Emelie Bardach, undated (Box 27)
  - Volume of press clippings, programs, etc., with a page of manuscript music presented to Eva Le Gallienne by A. M. Weil, 1932 (Box 27)
- Oversize Material, 1.25; (5 boxes) +1 portfolio, 1 broadside folder
  - From Series I:
    - L'Aiglon (Box 28)
    - Alice in Wonderland, 3 (Box 28)
    - Alison's House (Box 28)
    - Camille, 2 (Box 28)
    - Cherry Orchard, 2 (Box 29)
    - Cradle Song (Box 29)
    - Dear Jane (Box 29)
    - A Doll's House, 2 (Box 29)
    - The First Stone (Box 29)
    - The Good Hope (Box 29)
    - Hedda Gabler, 2 (Box 30)
    - Improvisations in June (Box 30)
    - L'Invitation au Voyage, 2 (Box 30)
    - John Gabriel Borkman (Box 30)
    - Katerina (Box 30)
    - Lady from Alfaqueque (Box 30)
    - Liliom (Box 30)
    - The Living Corpse (Box 30)
    - La Locandiera (Box 30)
    - Mademoiselle Bourrat (Box 30)
    - The Master Builder, 3 (Box 31)
    - On the High Road (Box 31)
    - Peter Pan (Box 31)
    - Romeo and Juliet (Box 31)
    - Rosmersholm (Box 31)
    - Saturday Night (Box 31)
    - The Sea Gull (Box 31)
    - Siegfried (Box 32)
    - The Three Sisters (Box 32)
    - Twelfth Night (Box 32)
    - 2 x 2 = 5 (Box 32)
    - The Women Have Their Way, 3 (Box 32)
    - The Would-Be-Gentleman, 2 (Box 32)
  - From Series III: Eva Le Gallienne scrapbook (Box 33 (Portfolio))
  - From Series III: Eva Le Gallienne press clippings, etc. (Box 34 (Broadside))